Hello friends. In this video, I want to
give you a tour of my Hermes setup, my
Hermes OS. It is a multi-agent system
that autonomously builds software, acts
[music] as a COO of my company,
assistant, and my personal productivity
and health coach, too. Honestly, [music]
I love Hermes. I use it every single
day, and I have so much fun building new
functionalities. So, I hope this video
gives you some ideas to build yours,
too. Now, without further ado, let's go.
A portion of this video is sponsored by
Hostinger.
So, first off, I want to show you Coder,
a multi-agent software building system.
So, let's actually build something right
now. This is my Discord where I talk to
my Hermes bot, so I can say, "Hermes
bot, draft me a spec to add on to my
Pomodoro app the ability to switch
skins." So, here's my little desktop
Pomodoro app. I can just put in the
time, label it, start the timer.
And once it's done, it shows up in my
Obsidian vault. I think it's already
very cute with this little avocado, but
it would be even cuter if it had the
ability to switch skins. Right now, it's
only an avocado. Please create three
other skins it can change to. For
example, cat, dog, uh tomato in the same
style. The user should be able to switch
skins easily. Keep everything else the
same.
And click enter. And then, a few minutes
later, we see that Hermes bot does its
thing. It comes up with a Pomodoro skin
that switcher PRD, tells me the goal is
to add a skin switching system to the
Pixel Pomodoro Electron app, so the user
can pick between existing pixel arts
with three different skins. And it goes
[music] on with a lot of details about
the approach for doing this. And I think
it looks pretty good. So, I'm going to
say, "Looks good. Let's build it." And
once it's done, it should show up in my
builds channel. So, we'll let this build
for now, and after it finishes, I
promise I'll explain a little bit more
about how this is all working under the
hood, as well. But, in the meantime, I
want to show you another functionality
in my Hermes setup called Lifebot. So,
this is Lifebot. Now, Lifebot I talk to
using Telegram. And as its name
suggests, it is my productivity and
health life coach. So, I can ask it,
"How is my productivity so far today?"
It's running some terminal commands.
Cool. And it tells me I have had three
sessions today of 27 minutes. So, film
prep, run script, and it also logged a
couple of test pomodoros that I did. Can
also ask it, "How many steps have I done
today?" And it says no data yet, but the
iCloud place order hasn't downloaded
locally. Okay, fine. I sync my steps
from my phone every 2 hours to Lifebot.
So, hasn't done that yet. That's okay.
You know what? Let's just say I'm going
to say, "What about yesterday? How many
steps?" It said I took 11,502
steps. Strong for a Sunday. Above my
average. Nice. So, this is all great,
you know, just like telling me
information, right? But what is really
valuable is actually hidden over here.
You see it has all this data that's
being logged into it, and it's able to
give me custom advice. I can ask it
questions like, "What's my average
amount of log time right now? And what
do you think I can do to help boost the
amount of focused time I work? Like
should I consider switching around my
times for when I do certain tasks, or
take more breaks?" And it can actually
tell me like what the pattern looks
like. "Your strongest windows by session
count is around like 12:00 p.m. That's
when I'm doing mostly tasks, organizing
light work. Around 5:00 p.m. I'm doing
mixed development and task. Around 7:00
p.m. I'm doing deep development,
scripting, and research." And etc. etc.,
right? And it's telling me that the gap
that I have is actually 9:00 a.m. to
11:00 a.m. It's saying that you're using
the 9:00 a.m. hour exactly once, and it
produced two solid sessions. So, it
tells me to try out that 9:00 to 11:00
a.m. slot to try to get more deep work
in earlier during the day. And it says
to don't overthink breaks. TLDR, you
don't need more breaks for longer
sessions. You need one more session per
day, ideally up in the 9:00 to 11:00
a.m. dead zone, or by protecting the
3:00 p.m. to 5:00 p.m. from task creep.
That alone will push you from four to
five sessions to five to six, and from
around 90 minutes to 110 plus minutes
per day of deep work. [music] Anyways, I
have dived a lot deeper into this with
Lifebot as well, but I hope this gives
you a good idea about how powerful it
can be when you can get custom advice
based upon the patterns that you have.
As I'm working as well, you know,
there's sometimes I'm just like, man,
like I'm so tired. What should I do?
Like should I like take a break right
now or should I like keep pushing
through it, right? So I can ask
something like, hey, I feel a bit tired.
Should I take a break right now or
should I push through another Pomodoro,
for example? And it's telling me it's
like 11:06 a.m. You've done one real
session and two one-minute tasks, so
that's like 27 minutes in total, so you
haven't actually logged a single break
yet. It tells me that my strongest
window at 12:00 p.m. opens in less than
an hour. So you're only at 27% of your
typical an hour and 40 minute day of
deep work, so the data says to push. But
if you do break, make it 10 minutes, no
more, no less, because we went through
this before. If I take breaks that are
like five minutes, it's basically just
procrastination. And if I take breaks
that are 15 minutes long, I just like
take the break, leave, and just like
never come back. Oh, cool. It also tells
me that it has decided to do a
self-improvement review. So that's
another like Hermie specialty, which if
you don't know what that means,
definitely check out the video which
I'll link over here, which is the
fundamentals video. Anyway, I hope this
little demo showcases how useful it is
to have something like Life Bot. I can
really say it has honestly, genuinely
changed my life. Now let's talk about
how Life Bot actually works under the
hood. So Life Bot is an agent that is
part of my entire multi-agent Hermie's
setup. And its job is to use data in
order to give me life coaching advice,
whether that be health goals or
productivity goals. Of course, as you
may have guessed, how good Life Bot is
depends on the data it actually has. And
right now it has three primary sources
of data. The Pomodoro logs which I
showed you earlier, whenever I do
Pomodoros, I use my little desktop app
to track how many minutes I'm doing and
what I'm doing during that time. And all
that gets stored locally into this
Obsidian vault. So here's some of my
logs. The second source of data is this
Typewriter desktop app, which I also
custom built. And on here I collect my
to-do lists, they today's video
production day, also different study
plans, and then I can like check things
off as I do them. And they're also
tracked over here Obsidian with
timestamps. And finally, the third
source of data is from my Apple Health.
I use iCloud and there to sync health
data from my phone. Right now, I'm
mostly only just tracked the steps, but
I have been thinking of whether I should
get like an Apple Watch or something so
I can have more data as well. Let me
know in the comments if you have an
Apple Watch. Do you think it's worth
getting? Cuz there are like a lot of
health metrics that I could be tracking.
But anyways, those are my three sources
of data and my Hermes Life Bot is able
to access all of this data and that's
how it's able to analyze it and give me
very constant based upon the data
[music] about me. Oh, and right now, the
model that's powering Life Bot is
DeepSeek V4 Pro. Although I do change
that model out. Like that's a hosted
version from the cloud, but sometimes I
also switch to a local model that I have
on my Mac Studio 2. Anyways, I don't
want to go into way too much more detail
about this and exactly how I built it
cuz that would be like a really really
long video. But I'm going to put a
summary of Life Bot's specs on screen
right now. So, please do take a
screenshot. This as usual would of
course also be in the free guide linked
in the description. And you know what? I
have actually been thinking whether I
should do like an entire Hermes workshop
because I genuinely think Hermes is is
so useful. So, if you're interested in
something like that, where I'll actually
explain how to actually build up these
functionalities and multi-agent systems,
do comment Hermes workshop because I
actually do monitor all the comments and
if I see a lot of interest, then I will
consider it. Anyways, let's actually go
back and see if Coder, our software
building agent, has finished building a
new skins for our Pomodoro app. Okay,
cool. So, it says build successful and
it gives me a bunch of information about
it. That's great. Let's actually see
what has built. Okay. So, go on terminal
and then let's see. Okay, and let's do
NPM start. And here we go. We have our
little Pomodoro here. Okay, great.
[music] So, it's over here. It'll do 1
minute. We'll do a test again. Test
skins. Start. And there's a button here.
So, here's the avocado. Drumroll,
please.
Cat. Hey, it's a cat. And dog. Hey, it's
a dog. And tomato.
There's a tomato. That tomato looks a
little bit creepy, but that's okay.
Yeah, so it did what it says it's going
to do, and now it has the ability to
have different skins. So, I don't know
about the aesthetics, especially the
tomato over here. It kind of looks a bit
creepy, so probably going to need to
like modify the aesthetics a little bit.
Time is up. There you have it. Now, let
me explain how it actually works under
the hood. So, Coder is another agent in
my Hermes multi-agent setup, and it's
specifically responsible for building
software. So, in terms of how it fits
together, the way I communicated with it
is through Discord as a Hermes bot. Now,
this Hermes bot itself is powered by a
local model on my Mac Studio called the
Quen 3.6 35B [music]
model. Oh, specifically the Quen 3.6 35B
A3B model. I can see it's a very popular
model with 5.4 million downloads just
last month. Anyways, I run this model
locally, and it's honestly a pretty good
model, but because I do pay for a Claude
Max subscription, and I actually want to
like use all of those tokens, right?
What I actually do is I use this model
to go and poke Claude code, and for
Claude code to actually write up the
entire spec of what I'm trying to build.
And it's actually Claude code that
actually goes and builds everything.
Then when it's done, it tells my local
Quen model, who then goes and tells me
that the thing is done building. It is
kind of complicated, but it's a
workaround because Anthropic doesn't
allow you to use your Claude
subscription directly, so that's why I
got to like do it this way. But hey, it
works out. I do sometimes just power
Hermes with other models as well, like
GPT models, Gemini models, and GLM and
DeepSeek. And that makes it a lot
easier. I'm going to put all of that on
screen right now along with summary
specs of the Coder agent. Oh yes, just
to mention, the way I'm coordinating all
of these multi-agents is with the Hermes
combat board. So yes, I saw in the
comments of my past video about what to
do if you want to run Hermes 24/7, but
you also don't have a dedicated machine.
Well, fret not because you can also run
it on a VPS, a virtual private server,
which is kind of like renting a machine
on the cloud. I actually also run
another instance of Hermes on our team's
VPS so that everybody else on our team
can also play around and build on top of
it, too. And that VPS is through
Hostinger, who are very kindly
sponsoring this portion of the video.
So, just like your local machine,
Hostinger keeps your API keys, data, and
logs all on your own private
infrastructure. And if you ever make
like a config mistake, you can just roll
it back because weekly backups are also
included by default. And guess what?
Hostinger actually has a pre-made Hermes
template already. So, you can go to
hostinger.com/tinahermes.
Under the Docker catalog, there is the
pre-built Hermes template pre-selected.
So, just click deploy. And that's it.
You get instant CLI access without any
manual configs. And since the entire VPS
is yours, it's not per agent fees. You
can run as many agents as your resources
allow. Our team VPS, for example, runs
Hermes agents and like six other
internal tools, too. So, if you want a
24/7 Hermes agent, but don't want to
deal with the hardware, you can use my
link hostinger.com/tinahermes
and apply my code Tina Huang for an
exclusive discount on the Hermes agent
VPS plan. Link in the description. Thank
you so much, Hostinger, for sponsoring
this portion of the video. Now, back to
the video. And with that, I want to move
on to Taco Bot, our Lonely Octopus SEO
agent and assistant. Lonely Octopus is
the name of my company, by the way, in
case you didn't [laughter] know.
All right. Let's go on to Lonely Octopus
team. So, here is the Lonely Octopus
Discord server, where all our Lonely
Octopus team hangs out. And as you can
see, there are many different channels.
So, Taco Bot can actually do a lot of
things. I will show you some of them.
This one is one of my favorite
functions. For example, I'm having this
conversation with Ibrahim from our team
about this teachable workshop that I'm
doing. Hope you guys went to that one,
cuz it probably has already passed by
the time you see this video. But, I can
say, "Hey Taco Bot, remind me at 9:00
p.m. today to decide which demos I will
do for the workshop." And then Taco Bot
does its thing, and it has set a
reminder for 9:00 p.m. today. Amazing.
Also, look, Taco Bot is a takoyaki.
Anyways, I love this function. I use it
so much. Like here, Taco Bot is
reminding me to review the deck for a
timer that I set earlier, and then I can
also reschedule it. Because we have so
much stuff going on this Discord as
well. Um I can also say go into this dev
channel and ask it, "Hey Tacobot, what
are people working on the past week?"
And Tacobot's able to scan this Discord
channel, and it's also linked to our
GitHub as well. It's able to tell me
that, "Okay, Rex is working on these
different things. Internal tool side,
Kauthar's working on this, Jonathan's
working on that, and then what's
happening on newsletter as well. What's
on? Etc. etc." Really handy for me as a
manager. And the final thing I want to
show you is on the COO side. You see,
the COO position for a startup, at least
a startup like us, has always been the
hardest thing to fill because it
involves having to document things and
make things sustainable while also
operating really quickly at the same
time. And honestly, I've been struggling
to fill the COO position of this company
for like years now. Until I realized
that Tacobot could do this. For example,
I can ask it I can say, "Tacobot, draft
me an ops guide for how our team
releases internal software. All the
steps that we follow and sanity checks."
And Tacobot's able to gather information
from this Discord, and it also has
access to our notion where we have so
much data stored there, as well as our
Slack, which we use for external
contractors and external people we work
with. So, it's able to look through all
of this to be able to drop up these ops
guides. So, you can see here that it's
specifically searching through notion
right now. And we're able to know that
say for example, pre-release checklist
and sanity checks. So, we know that for
coding quality checks, we need to have
at least one PR review minimum one PR
approval to GitHub PR against main,
automated test all units integrations,
blah blah blah, etc. etc., right? And
release execution protocol. So, this is
the way that we execute things. So, if
anybody wants to know, they can just ask
Tacobot. And we have new people who are
going to be onboarding into our team. We
can also give them access to Tacobot.
So, they can learn how we do things. I
hope you can see how powerful this
system is. Especially times 10 because
that's the size of our core team. It has
made our operations so much more
efficient. So, to summarize, the way
that Talk About works is that it has
access to all these different data
sources, like Discord, Notion, Slack,
Google Drive, YouTube, Instagram, social
media accounts, data bases, and all our
internal tools as well. It is able to
use this data in order to inform the
team of what's happening. And at the
same time, it also performs assistance
functions, like being able to search for
things, remind you of things. And it's
also the CEO of this company where it's
making documentations of how we do
certain things, onboarding new members,
and giving suggestions for how we can
operate better as a team. Model-wise, I
started off with Gemini 3.6 Flash, cuz
it's a very fast model and easy to test,
but I'm slowly migrating to local models
instead to make sure that everything
[music] is kept private, hosted on our
Mac Studio. Put all of this summary on
screen now. Please take a screenshot.
Also, I'll link it in the free guide in
the description, and I'll provide a
little bit more detail about the specs
that's being built cuz can't fit
everything into one screenshot. Do check
it out. Okay, so covered, I would say,
the three functionalities of Hermes that
I use the most, personally. Of course,
I'm still learning and I'm building new
things literally every day to my Hermes
as well. So, if you're asking me in a
month, probably going to be more here as
well. But before I end this video, I do
want to have a section where I cover
some of my regularly scheduled cron jobs
that are maybe like less sexy, but they
are still very useful, and they also
help keep the whole system running. And
that is specifically the alerts channel.
See, the alerts channel is not sexy, but
it's where I get alerts from all the
different agents that are running in my
Hermes. And they all check in at a
different schedule, like once a day or
weekly, telling me that everything is
operating as intended, there's no
security breaches, and any suggestions
and things they may come across that I
could potentially be working on. Like I
said, not sexy, right? But this part of
the entire Hermes system is really
important, cuz it's how I make sure that
everything is operating smoothly and I'm
building things in a sustainable way.
Not going to go into way too much
details about this, but you know the
drill, I will put on screen now a
summary of all the different check-ins
and alerts and security systems that I
have implemented. And finally, before I
end this video, I do want to mention
that I am working on a more complicated
agentic system as well within Hermes.
The concept is to be constantly
researching different topics related to
like AI and tech and education because,
you know, that's the niche that I'm in,
evaluating it and giving me suggestions
on different content ideas and software
that I could be building, either like
internal software or external software.
So, I'm still in the very beginning
stages of this. I'm not ready to show
you guys yet, but wanted to get let you
guys know what I'm working on right now
because this kind of thing is totally
possible. I'm just still like tuning it.
I think once I manage to get it set up
that it can autonomously be like
scraping the internet, that will be a
very, very cool and very powerful
system. So, yes, for now, this is my
Hermes setup. I hope this was
interesting for you guys to see what
I've built, and I'm curious, what have
you built in your Hermes? What do you
want to be building in your Hermes now
that you've watched this video? And
again, please let me know in the
comments, just write like Hermes
workshop or something like that, and
that will let me know how much interest
there is in doing a Hermes workshop, and
maybe we'll do one. But for now, have a
wonderful rest of your day, and I will
see you guys in the next video or live
stream.